### Shin Hwei Tan

### **Assistant Professor**

Southern University of Science and Technology (SUSTech)

shinhwei@hotmail.com

Webpage: http://www.shinhwei.com/

DBLP: https://dblp.uni-trier.de/pers/hd/t/Tan:Shin Hwei

Google Scholar: <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=1eFjFs8AAAAJ&hl=en">https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=1eFjFs8AAAAJ&hl=en</a>

# Research Interests

My main research interest is in the field of software engineering, specifically on automated bug-fixing and software testing. I have proposed new methods and developed tools to facilitate dynamic code-comment analysis using test generation tool and automated repair of software regressions and Android apps. I am currently looking at methods in building the next generation automated bug-fixing approach.

#### Education

### National University of Singapore, Singapore

Ph.D., School of Computing, August 2012-March 2018 CAP: 4.38/5.00

Thesis Topic: Design of Repair Operators for Self-Healing Software Systems

Adviser: Abhik Roychoudhury

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Champaign, IL

M.S., Computer Science, May 2012

GPA: 3.91/4.00

Thesis Topic: @tComment: Testing Javadoc Comments to Detect Comment-Code

Inconsistencies

Advisers: Darko Marinov, Lin Tan

B.S. (Hons), Computer Science, May 2010

Thesis Topic: Theories/Parameterized tests for JUnit

Adviser: Darko Marinov

### Grants

• "Research on patch generation algorithm and automated repair system for Android apps", Young Researcher Fund 2019, National Natural Science Foundation of China, Grant No. 61902170, \$270k

GPA: 3.68/4.00

• "Automated Testing and Repair for Android Apps", PI for General Program 2020, Natural Science Foundation of Guangdong Province, \$100k

## Awards and Honors

- Dean's Graduate Research Excellence Award (2016)
- Google Anita Borg Memorial Scholarship (2015) for encouraging female presence in computing and technology.
- Research Achievement Award (2015)
- David J. Kuck Outstanding MS Thesis Award (2013)
- Singapore International Graduate Award (2012-2015)
- ACM-W Scholarship (2012) for attendance of conference for female researchers
- Malaysian Government Scholarship (2006-2010)
- Rockwell Collins Scholarship (2009)
- Motorola Academic Scholarship (2008)

#### Services

- Founder and Advisor for Women in Engineering in SUSTech
- Maintainer of a blog, https://cstrigirls.blogspot.sg/, that focuses on giving academic advice to female computing students in Asia-Pacific countries.
- Mentor in Women in Engineering in University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign
- ACM Student Research Competition @ICSE 2019
  - o My student won bronze metal in the competition
- Coach for National Student Contest for Software Testing Competition in China
  - o My student won first prize in the contest

# Conference /Workshop Publications

- 1. M. Wu, L. Zhang, C. Liu, S. H. Tan, Y. Zhang. *Automating CUDA Synchronization via Program Transformation* In: Automated Software Engineering (ASE 2019), Nov 2019. (acceptance: 20.9%)
- 2. Y. Wang, M. Wen, R. Wu, Z. Liu, <u>S.H. Tan</u>, Z. Zhu, H. Yu and S.C Cheung. *Can I Have a Stack Trace to Examine the Dependency Conflict Issue?* In: International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE 2019), May 2019. (acceptance: 20.6%)
- 3. X. Gao, <u>S.H. Tan</u>, Z. Dong, and A. Roychoudhury. *Android Testing via Synthetic Symbolic Execution*. In 33rd IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE 2018). (acceptance: 19.9%)
- 4. <u>S. H. Tan</u>, Z. Dong. X. Gao, A. Roychoudhury. *Repairing Crashes in Android Apps*. In: International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE 2018), May 2018. (acceptance: 20.9%)
- 5. J. Yi, U.Z. Ahmed, A. Karkare, S.H. Tan, A.Roychoudhury. *A Feasibility Study of Using Automated Program Repair for Introductory Programming Assignments*. In: Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE 2017), Sept 2017. (acceptance: 24.4%)
- 6. <u>S. H. Tan.</u> H. Yoshida, M. Prasad and A. Roychoudhury. *Anti-patterns in Search-based Program Repair*, In:Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE 2016), Nov 2016 (acceptance: 27.1%)
- 7. <u>S. H. Tan</u>, A. Roychoudhury. *Relifix: Automated Repair of Software Regressions*. In: International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE 2015), May 2015 (acceptance: 18.5%)
- 8. J. Yi, D. Qi, S. H. Tan, A. Roychoudhury. Expressing and Checking Intended Changes via Software Change Contracts. In: International Symposium on Software Testing and Analysis (ISSTA 2013), Lugano, Switzerland, July 2013. (acceptance: 26%)
- 9. <u>S. H. Tan,</u> D. Marinov, L. Tan, and G. T. Leavens. *@tComment: Testing Javadoc Comments to Detect Comment-Code Inconsistencies*. In: International Conference on Software Testing, Verification, and Validation (ICST 2012), pages 260-269, Montreal, Canada, April 2012. (acceptance: 27%)

# Journal Publications

- 1. S. Mechtaev, X. Gao, S. H. Tan, A. Roychoudhury. *Test-equivalence Analysis for Automatic Patch Generation*. In ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM), To appear, July 2018
- 2. J. Yi, <u>S.H. Tan</u>, S. Mechtaev, M. Boehme, A.Roychoudhury. A correlation study between automated program repair and test-suite metrics. In: Empirical Software Journal (EMSE 2018).
- 3. J. Yi, D. Qi, <u>S. H. Tan</u>, A. Roychoudhury. *Software Change Contracts*. In ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM), pages 18:1-18:43, May 2015.

# Workshop/ Poster Publications

- 1. B. Baudry, N. Harrand, E. Schulte, C. Timperley, S. H. Tan, M. Selakovic, E. Ugherughe. *A spoonful of DevOps helps the GI go down*. In 4th International Genetic Improvement Workshop, May 2018.
- 2. <u>S. H. Tan</u>, J. Yi, Yulis, S. Mechtaev, A. Roychoudhury. *Codeflaws: A Programming Competition Benchmark for Evaluating Automated Program Repair Tools*. In: International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE 2017 Poster), May 2017.
- 3. B. Daniel, D. Dig, T. Gvero, V. Jagannath, J. Jiaa, D. Mitchell, J. Nogiec, S. H. Tan, and D. Marinov. *ReAssert: A Tool for Repairing Broken Unit Tests*. In: International Conference on Software Engineering, Demonstrations Track (ICSE Demo 2011), pages 1010-1012, Honolulu, HI, May 2011. (acceptance: 37%)

### **Patents**

• Software program repair, H. Yoshida, S. H. Tan, M. R. Prasad, US20170060735A1

# Professional Activities

- ISSTA 2020, Student Volunteer Co-Chair
- FSE 2020, Program Committee
- International Workshop for Automated Program Repair @ ICSE2020, Co-Organizer
- ASE 2019, Configuration and Variability, Session Chair
- First International Workshop on Software Engineering Intelligence 2019, PC
- Workshop on Intelligent Bug Fixing @ SANER 2019, PC
- ICSE 2020, Program Committee
- ASE 2019, Program Committee
- ESEC/FSE 2019, Tool Demo Program Committee
- ICSE 2019, PC for Student Research Competition
- Genetic Improvement Workshop (GI 2019) @ ICSE2019, Co-organizer
- GECCO 2018, PC for Genetic Improvement Workshop
- ISSTA 2014, Artifact Evaluation Committee
- ICSE 2015 (NIER), Co-reviewer
- Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology (TOSEM), Reviewer
- Empirical Software Engineering Journal (EMSE), Reviewer
- Transactions on Software Engineering (TSE), Reviewer

# Teaching Experience

# **Southern University of Science and Technology**, China

Sole Instructor for CS 304 Software Engineering

Feb. 2019 to . June 2019

- Conduct lectures and labs for 156 students
- Prepared teaching materials for 2 hours weekly lectures and 2 hours weekly labs
  Design course project for finding bugs in open-source Android apps

Sole Instructor for CS 409 Software Testing

Aug. 2018 to Dec. 2018

- Proposed the first course in Software Testing in SUSTech
- Design course syllabus and prepared teaching materials for 29 students
- Design course project for finding bugs in open-source Android apps

### National University of Singapore, Singapore

Teaching Assistant for CS 4218 Software Testing

Aug. 2012 to May 2013

- Designed courses structure and prepared material for first software testing class
- Graded weekly programming homework

### University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, Champaign, IL

Teaching Assistant for CS242: Programming Studio Laboratory Aug. 2011 to May 2012

• Supervised programming assign` ments presentation for 5-6 students per section

Teaching Assistant for CS427: Software Engineering I Aug. 2010 to May 2011 Fall 2010 and Fall 2011

- Advised students for course project for Eclipse refactoring engines
- Graded bi-weekly programming assignments for 20 groups of students

Teaching Assistant for CS428: Software Engineering II
Spring 2011

Jan. 2010 to Dec. 2011

- Provided support for online students through the Illinois Internet Computer Science Program (I2CS)
- Conduct bi-weekly meeting with students for course projects to develop games, mobile applications, websites.

Laboratory Helper for CS 102: Little Bits to Big Ideas Aug. 2009 to May 2009

- Assisted non-majors in two consecutive laboratory sessions
- Graded student programming assignments

Program Repair Workshop@NASAC  Repairing crashes in Android apps Chinese Search-based Software Engineering Workshop  17 Nov. 2018
Chinese Search-based Software Engineering Workshop
Repairing crashes in Android apps 16 Nov. 2018
Peking University
Repairing crashes in Android apps 22 June 2018
Wuhan University
Repairing crashes in Android apps 30 Jan. 2018
GI-Dagstuhl Seminars, Germany
Design of Repair Operators for Automated Program Repair 30 Jan. 2017
50th CREST Open Workshop, University of College London
Anti-patterns in Search-based Program Repair 20 Sept. 2016
Microsoft PhD Forum 2016, Microsoft Research Asia, Beijing, China
Conference Test-equivalence Analysis for Automatic Patch Generation 29 May. 2019
Talks International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE) 2019
Anti-patterns in Search-based Program Repair 17 Nov. 2016
Foundations of Software Engineering (FSE) 2016
Relifix: Automated Repair of Software Regressions 21 May 2015
International Conference on Software Engineering (ICSE) 2015
@tComment: Testing Javadoc Comments to Detect 19 April 2012
Comment-Code Inconsistencies
International Conference on Software Testing, Verification & Validation (ICST) 2012
Work NUS-Singtel Cyber Security Research and Development Lab, Singapore
Experience Research Assistant Nov. 2017 to May 2018
<ul> <li>Core developer and inventor for automated repair of crashes for Android apps</li> </ul>
Fujitsu Laboratories of America, Sunnyvale, CA, USA
Research Intern Feb. 2015 to May 2015
<ul> <li>Conduct study of the common characteristics of automatically generated patches</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Developed techniques for improving search-based automated program repair</li> </ul>
Intel Corporation, Penang, Malaysia
Summer Intern for Testing Hole Resolution (THR)  June 2011 to Aug. 2011
<ul> <li>Developed automation for improving efficiency in running automated tests</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Implemented features and developed error handling for program in Perl and Tcl</li> </ul>
Railroad Department, Champaign, IL, USA
Undergraduate Assistant Aug. 2007 to May. 2009
<ul> <li>Maintained MS Access database for daily tank car accident reports</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>Debugged and programmed using Visual Basic, Ruby, and HTML</li> </ul>
• Hsu Myat Win - Co-advised with Prof. Yulei Sui (SUSTECH-UTS Joint PhD program
Students       Zhiyu Fan - Co-advised with Prof. Abhik Roychoudhury at NUS     Zigiang Li - SUSTech Master program 2019

- Ziqiang Li SUSTech Master program 2019
- Xiaowen Zhang SUSTech Master program 2019
- **Software Skills** Computer Programming: Java, Python, C, C++, OCAML
  - Version Control: DVCS (Mercurial, Git), and VCS (CVS, SVN)
  - Software Testing: Randoop, JUnit, KLEE

### References

## Abhik Roychoudhury (thesis advisor)

Professor
School of Computing
National University of Singapore
13 Computing Drive
Singapore 117417
Republic of Singapore.
+65-65168939

https://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~abhik/abhik@comp.nus.edu.sg

### Lin Tan

Associate Professor, PEng
Department of Computer Science
Purdue University
305 N. University Street
West Lafayette, IN 47907
USA
+1-765-494-7190
https://www.cs.purdue.edu/homes/lintan/lintan@purdue.edu

### **Darko Marinov**

Associate Professor
Department of Computer Science
University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign
4233 Siebel Center
201 N. Goodwin Ave.
Urbana, IL 61801
USA
+1-217-265-6117
http://mir.cs.illinois.edu/marinov/
marinov@illinois.edu

### Mukul R. Prasad

Research Manager
Software Quality & Security Laboratory
Fujitsu Laboratories of America
1240 E. Arques Ave., M/S 345
Sunnyvale, CA 94085
USA
+1-408-530-4628
mukul@us.fujitsu.com